FREDNEL JEAN-JOSEPH

Full stack Web Developer

Portfolio / GitHub / LinkedIn / Email

Summary

Entrepreneurial full-stack web developer heavily focusing on web development. My ultimately goal is to build value by maintaining and/or building projects of highest quality to better our community, and to contribute to the growth of our environment. I have experience working in teams as well as without supervision as I am flexible, adaptable, and very passionate about delivering the best technical solutions.

Education

Grand Circus of Detroit – April to June 2021

- Fulltime/Daytime full stack C#/.NET Bootcamp
- Backend C#/Net, MVC, SQL and SSMS, Web API
- Frontend JavaScript, TypeScript/Angular, HTML/CSS/Bootstrap

East Carolina University - Spring 2018 to Summer 2019

- BSBA Management Information System
- GPA 3.775/4.00

Technical Skills

Backend

- C#/.NET, ASP.NET MVC, Web API
- Ling2SQL, ADO.Net, DSA

Databases

- MS SQL Server, CRUD, Dapper
- Entity Framework, SSRS, SSIS
- SQLite, ORM, T-SQL

Frontend

- JavaScript, Typescript/Angular
- HTML5, JSON, CSS3, Bootstrap

SDLC

- 12 Factor App, Agile, BRD
- OOP, SOLID Principle
- Data Structure & Algorithm

Experiences

Accenture PLC / CRM Analyst - 05/2019 to 04/2021

- Provided helpdesk support for North Carolina State Purchasing System, NC eProcurement.
- Resolved technical problems relating to business-critical customer facing portal resulting in system performance and scalability improvements.
- Diagnosed, troubleshoot, and resolved ranges of software, and connectivity issues. Exceled at probing and researching, analyzing, and rectifying problems.
- Received excellent evaluations on monthly performance reviews for teamwork, customer service, communication skills and technical problem-solving.
- Software used to perform daily tasks include ServiceNow CRM, PowerBI, Advanced Excel, JIRA, and the continuous learning of the new software as they become necessary tools to solve customer related issues.

Keller Williams Realty / Real Estate Agent - 08/2016 to 06/2018

- Managed negotiation process with all involving in the buying process ensuring that clients understand their home purchase and closing process.
- Build and nurtured client relationship and deliver exceptional client satisfaction.
- Developed and maintain excellent relationships with relevant organization and influencers.

Sprint Nextel / Lead Retail Sales Consultant – 10/2006 to 02/2017

- Delivered sales and profit growth through strategic sales practices that resulted in 31% and above sales increase month over month.
- Recruited, trained, and retained exceptional team members.
- Analyzed business strategies and processes to determine gaps and developed action plans to improve performance.
- Oversaw store operation and established daily and weekly cash reconciliation process.
- Handled customer complaints and escalations and reduced churn by 50% month over month.